字幕來源：網絡
后期：Lee.
今夜
This is the night
小姐與流浪漢
真美妙
It's a beautiful night
我們叫它愛的夜晚
And they call it bella notte
仰望星空
Look at the skies
布滿星辰
They have stars in their eyes
就在這醉人的愛的夜晚
On this lovely bella notte
守護著
So take the love
你所愛的人
Of your loved one
小心地守護著
You'll need it about this time
當你沉迷愛中
To keep from falling like a star
不要讓愛像流星墜落
When you make that dizzy climb
今夜
For this is the night
如置身天堂
And the heavens are right
就在這醉人的
On this lovely
愛的夜晚
Bella notte
就在這醉人的
On this lovely
愛的夜晚
Bella notte
世界上有一件事  金錢買不到
就是人類與狗的友誼
喬許比林斯
謹以本片
獻給人類忠誠的好朋友
雪花在夜里輕輕飄下
Silent as a snowflake in the night
圣潔的夜
Holy is the spirit of this night
世界安詳平和
All the world is calm and peaceful
充滿光明歡樂
All the world is bright and joyful
愛的真諦
Spirit of love
與平安
And child of peace
無止境的愛
Love unending
永不停歇
That shall not cease
保佑我
Peace, my children
善良的孩子
Of good will
保佑我善良的孩子
Peace, my children
平安永跟隨
Peace, be still
親愛的  這個送你
It's for you, darling.
圣誕快樂
Merry Christmas.
哦  親愛的吉姆
Oh, Jim, dear.
你知道我想要什么  對不對
It's the one I was admiring, isn't it?
有蝴蝶結
Trimmed with ribbons?
是有蝴蝶結
Well, it has a ribbon.
好可愛
Oh, how sweet.
-親愛的  你喜歡嗎  -我愛死了
-You like her, darling? -Oh, I love her.
可愛的小狗狗
What a perfectly beautiful little lady.
來  麗滴  過來
Come on, Lady. Over here.
乖
That's a girl.
來  這是你的小床
There, now. A nice little bed for you.
迪爾  她睡這里不會著涼嗎
But Jim, dear, are you sure she'll be warm enough?
當然不會  她會在這個溫暖的小窩
Why, of course, darling. She'll be snug as a bug in a... uh-oh.
差點忘了
Almost forgot something.
來
There.
麗滴  晚安
Good night, Lady.
達玲  別擔心
Now, now, don't worry, darling.
她一會就睡著了
She'll go right to sleep.
不  麗滴
No, no, Lady.
你的床在這里
This is where you belong, right here.
你看  她很寂寞的
Aw, look. She's lonesome.
也許我們  今晚就好了
Don't you think maybe...? Just for tonight?
達玲  一開始就訓練
Now, darling, if we're going to show her who's master,
她才會聽話
we must be firm from the very beginning.
麗滴
Lady!
別叫了
Stop that now!
別叫
Stop it!
麗滴  安靜  聽到沒
Lady! Quiet, now. You hear me?
上床去
Back to bed!
快
Quick, now.
別再吵
Not one more sound.
吉姆
Jim, dear.
-吉姆  -怎么啦
-Aw, Jim. -Hm? What?
好吧
Oh, all right.
記住  下不為例
But remember, just for tonight.
好  麗滴
All right, Lady. All right.
麗滴  我起來了
I'm up. I'm up, Lady. I...
哦  不
Oh, no!
吉姆  怎么啦
What's wrong, Jim? What is it?
你可不可以告訴她  今天是星期天
Can't you explain to Lady about Sundays?
慘案發生
達玲  你有沒有發現  有了麗滴之后
Have you noticed, darling, since we've had Lady,
我們就很少看  讓人心煩的頭條新聞了
we see less and less of those disturbing headlines?
對  要是沒有她  日子該怎么過
Yes, I just don't know how we ever got along without her.
她有六個月大了吧
Say, she must be about six months old.
我們最好趕快幫她辦戶口
We'd better be getting her a licence.
希望大小剛剛好
Hope it fits.
真漂亮
My, but it does look nice.
女大十八變
So grown up.
加克和查弟  一定會大吃一驚的
Won't Jock and Trusty be surprised?
往前四步  再左轉
Four steps straight and then to the left
就到了我的秘密基地
And right to the place where I marked it
后院里有我藏的寶貝
With a bonnie, bonnie bone that I buried for me own
In my bonnie, bonnie bank in the backyard
哇  太棒了
That's a grand sight.
加克
Jock!
Oh, Jock!
嗨  加克
Hello, Jock.
哦  是你啊  小美人
Oh! Oh, it's you, lassie.
看得出來我哪里不一樣嗎
Notice anything different?
你洗了澡
Eh... You've had a bath?
不對
No, not that.
你修了指甲
You've had your nails clipped?
再猜
Guess again.
我猜不出來
Well, I wouldn't a-be a-knowing.
哇  小美人
Why, lassie.
新項圈
A bonnie new collar.
-喜歡嗎  -喜歡
-Do you like it? -Aye.
一定很貴
Hm... It must be very expensive.
-查弟看過沒  -還沒
-Have you shown it to Trusty yet? -No.
我們趕快去找他
We'd best go at once.
他對這種事很敏感
You know how sensitive he is about these things.
他在做夢
He's dreaming.
對
Aye.
夢見他跟他爺爺
Dreamin' of those bonnie bygone days
千辛萬苦在沼澤里
when he and his grandfather were trackin' criminals
追蹤壞人的英勇往事
through the swamps.
-真的嗎  -但那是
-They were? -But that was before...
是怎樣
Before what?
小美人  該告訴你實話了
'Tis time you knew the truth, lassie.
這種事不該發生在狗身上
It shouldn't have happened to a dog.
但是
But, well...
查弟失去了嗅覺
Trusty has lost his sense of smell.
-不會吧  -真的
-No! -Aye.
小美人我們不能告訴他
But we must never let on that we know, lassie.
他一定會非常傷心的
It would break his poor heart.
他跑哪去了  他跑哪去了
Which way did he go? Which way did he go?
-誰  -一個大家伙
-Go? -Yeah, big fella.
差不多有六尺兩寸
About, uh, six-foot-two.
不  三寸
No, uh, three.
穿條紋裝  沒戴項圈
Wore a striped suit. No collar. Uh...
哇  麗滴小姐
Why, Miss Lady.
你戴項圈了
You have a collar.
還有身份證
And a licence.
我的天
My, my.
-光陰似箭  -對
-How time does fly. -Aye.
她拿迪爾的拖鞋磨牙
It seems only yesterday she was cuttin' her teeth
好像才是昨天的事
on Jim Dear's slippers,
現在她已經亭亭玉立了
and now there she is, a full-grown lady.
戴著榮譽勛章
wearing the greatest honour man can bestow.
代表忠誠與地位
The badge of faith and respectability.
對  麗滴小姐
That's right, Miss Lady.
就像我爺爺以前常說
As my grandpappy, Old Reliable, used to say...
我有沒有提過我爺爺
I don't recollect if I've ever mentioned Old Reliable before.
有
Aye, you have, laddie.
對哦
Oh, yeah.
是吉姆迪爾
Ooh! It's Jim Dear.
失陪了
Please excuse me.
麗滴  你在這里
Hello, there, Lady.
來  看誰先到家
Come on, beat you home.
你又贏了
Oh... You win again.
站好
Steady, now.
別動
Steady.
這是什么
Well, what have we here? Oh...
長大了對不對
Big girl now, huh?
好
All right.
女士優先
Oh. Ladies first.
達玲  有麗滴陪我們
You know, darling, with Lady here,
人生就沒有遺憾了
I'd say life is quite complete.
是啊  迪爾
Yes, dear.
沒有什么能取代  她在我們心中的地位
I don't imagine anything could ever take her place in our hearts.
真舒服
What a day!
該去弄點早餐了
Well, now to dig up some breakfast.
書
小狗特價
燃料與飼料
可愛的小家伙
Aw. Cute little rascals.
我看看早餐要吃什么
Now. That breakfast, let's see.
伯尼
Bernie's?
伯尼燒烤
不  法蘭克斯
Hm. No. Francois...
法蘭克斯面包店
不
No, no.
不  太多淀粉了
Nope. Too much starch. Ah!
湯尼之家  對
Tony's. Oh, that's it.
一個禮拜沒來了
I haven't been there in a week.
這樣的好天氣  正適合做比薩
A beautiful day to make pizza
嘿  我們還是叫它  愛的夜晚
Hey, still we call it bella notte
是長云
Well, buon giorno, Butch.
你要來吃早餐嗎
You want-a your breakfast, eh?
好  老板幫你留了些上好的料
OK. The boss, he's a-saving some a-nice bones for you.
準備到左半場接球
Breakfast coming up from a-left field.
接得好
Good catch!
慢點  小子
Whoa, boy, whoa.
捕狗隊
警告
未戴項圈的流浪狗
將依市府規定  立即逮捕
Hey. Psst!
嘿
Psst!
我的天
Blimey.
-佩姬  是長云  -噓
-Look, Peg, it's the tramp. -Shh!
嗨  帥哥  一起來狂歡吧
Hiya, handsome. Come to join the party?
好了  沒時間耍嘴皮
All right, all right. No time for wisecracks.
我先救你們出來
I've got to get you out.
情況不妙  到處都是警示
I'm telling you, the pressure's really on. Signs all over town.
-謝啦  -你真好
-Gee, thanks. -You're a bit of all right, chum.
-好  趕快走  -嘿  搞什么
-OK, OK, get going. -Hey! What's going on over there?
快走  小心點
Scram. And be careful.
你這只臟狗
Why, you mangy mutt.
放開  放開我
Hey. Let go. Let go of me. Ah!
有錢人的地盤
Well. Snob hill! Ha.
嗨  女孩們  你們好嗎
Hi, gals. How's pickings?
不太好
Pretty slim, eh?
對  我相信  每個垃圾桶都有蓋子
Yeah. I'll bet they've got a lid on every trash can.
連樹都有籬笆圈住
And a fence around every tree.
天知道那些栓皮帶  戴項圈的家伙有什么樂趣
I wonder what the leash and collar set does for excitement.
小美女
Lassie. Lassie!
麗滴小姐
Oh, Miss Lady, ma'am.
Miss Lady!
早安  小美女
Ah! Good morning, lassie.
今天天氣
'Tis a bonnie, braw, bright day... Eh...
真好啊
...day.
麗滴小姐
Why, Miss Lady.
怎么啦
Is something wrong?
對  小美女  告訴我們
Aye. Tell us, lassie.
-如果有人欺負你  -不  加克
-If somebody's been mistreatin' ya... -Oh, no, Jock.
我一定做錯了什么
It's something I've done, I guess.
你
You?
一定是
It must be.
吉姆迪爾和達玲對我好
Jim Dear and Darling are acting so...
-吉姆迪爾和達玲  -閉嘴
-Jim Dear and Darling? -Hush, lad.
小美女  說清楚一點
Now, lassie, get on with the details.
首先我注意到
Well, I first noticed it
有一天吉姆迪爾回家時
the other day when Jim Dear came home.
麗滴  不要
Down, Lady, down!
達玲  達玲
Darling, darling!
你還好吧
Are you all right?
我當然好  怎么會不好
Of course I am. Why shouldn't I be?
我就是放心不下
I just can't help worrying.
以你現在的情況
After all, in your condition,
一個人在家
alone here all day,
還要蹓那只狗
and walking that dog...
-那只狗  -那只狗
-That dog! -That dog?
他從來沒有這樣叫過我
He's never called me that before.
小美女
Well, now, lassie,
別太多心了
I wouldn't worry my wee head about that.
記住  他們畢竟是人
Remember, they're only humans, after all.
對  麗滴小姐
That's right, Miss Lady.
就像我爺爺以前常說
As my grandpappy, Old Reliable, used to say...
我有沒有提過我爺爺
I don't recollect if I've ever mentioned Old Reliable before.
有
Aye, you have, laddie.
-講過八百遍了  -對
-Uh, frequently. -Oh, yeah.
但現在達玲
But now Darling is... Well...
我們每天下午  都會一起玩
We've always enjoyed our afternoon romp together.
但是昨天
But yesterday...
不  麗滴  今天不去散步
No, Lady. No walk today.
不  麗滴
No, Lady.
現在不行
Not now.
麗滴
Lady!
麗滴  放下
Drop that, Lady.
我說放下
Drop it, I say.
其實不會痛
It didn't hurt, really.
但是達玲從來沒打過我
But Darling has never struck me... before.
小美女
Now, lassie.
別放在心上
Do not take it too seriously.
畢竟這種事
After all, at a time like this...
麗滴小姐  你看
Why, yes, you see, Miss Lady,
人類一生中都會發生
there comes a time in the life of all humans when, uh...
他們說是
Well, as they put it, uh...
那件事嗎
Birds and the bees?
或是  怎么說
Or... Well, uh...
送子鳥  不是
The stork? You know... Uh, no?
-嗯  小美女  -他的意思是
-Well, uh... -What he's trying to say, lassie,
達玲要生孩子了
is Darling is expecting a wee bairn.
孩子
Bairn?
麗滴小姐  他是說小寶寶
He means a baby, Miss Lady.
哦
Oh.
什么是小寶寶
What's a baby?
是人
Well, they resemble humans.
但很小
But I'd say a mite smaller.
對  用爬的
Aye. And they walk on all fours.
如果我記得沒錯  他們叫起來很大聲
And if I remember correctly, they bellow a lot.
對  而且很花錢
Aye. And they're very expensive.
你不能跟他們玩
You will not be permitted to play with it.
但他們很可愛
But they're mighty sweet.
軟綿綿的
And very, very soft.
只是可愛的
Just a cute little bundle.
小麻煩
Of trouble.
對  他們亂抓亂捏  拉耳朵
Yeah. They scratch, pinch, pull ears...
沒什么了  每只狗都受得了
Ah, but shucks. Any dog can take that.
他們就是這樣  破壞你甜蜜的家
It's what they do to your happy home.
閃一邊好嗎
Move it over, will you, friend?
他們是破壞狂
Homewreckers, that's what they are.
你是誰  憑什么闖進來
Look here. Who are you to barge in?
小子  我是過來人
The voice of experience, buster.
等到小孩生下來
Just wait till junior gets here.
當你很想有人幫你抓癢
You get the urge for a nice comfortable scratch,
就有人會說  "把狗弄出去
and... "Put that dog out!
他會把跳蚤傳給小寶寶"
He'll get fleas all over the baby."
你朝陌生狗大叫
You start barking at some strange mutt.
"別叫了  小寶寶會被你吵醒"
"Stop that racket. You'll wake the baby."
然后
And then!
他們把你打入冷宮
Then they hit you in the room and board department.
記得那些大魚大肉嗎
Remember those nice, juicy cuts of beef?
想都別想
Forget them.
吃寶寶吃剩的吧
Leftover baby food.
還有爐火旁  那張溫暖的床嗎
And that nice, warm bed by the fire?
變成漏水的狗屋
A leaky doghouse.
-老天  小美女  -別聽他胡說
-Oh, dear. -Do not listen, lassie.
沒有人會那么殘忍
No human is that cruel.
麗滴小姐  當然不會
Of course not, Miss Lady.
大家都知道
Why, everybody knows
人類是狗最好的朋友
a dog's best friend is his human.
拜托
Oh, come on now, fellas.
你還沒上過當是嗎
Oh, you haven't fallen for that old line, now have you?
對  你這個混混
Aye. And we've no need for mongrels
別在這里胡說八道
and their radical ideas.
走開
Off with you, now. Off with you!
-好  小家伙  -我叫加克
-OK, Sandy. -The name's Jock.
-好  加克  -快滾
-OK, Jock. -Heather Lad of Glencairn to you!
好  好  好
OK, OK, OK.
但是記住
But remember this, Pigeon.
人類的愛是有限的
A human heart has only so much room for love and affection.
當小寶寶降臨
When a baby moves in,
狗就一邊涼快吧
the dog moves out.
十二月  一月
二月  三月
四月
我看看  差不多是
Let's see. That'll be about...
算了
Oh, well.
十一月
十二月
達玲
Darling?
耶魯
我們不知道  是男孩還是女孩對不對
There isn't any way we can tell, for sure, what it's going to be, is there?
不知道  沒有人說得準
I'm afraid not. Nobody ever knows for certain.
貝蒂安  貝蒂露
貝蒂露安
我們只能滿懷希望
All we can do is hope.
一月
麗滴
達玲  你真的要吃西瓜
Darling, are you sure you want watermelon?
還要一些牛雜
Oh! And some chop suey too.
牛
Chop su...
達玲  好
All right, darling.
二月
天使就要降臨
沒見過這么可愛的
That's the cutest thing I ever saw.
這些小鞋子
What darling little booties!
-那頂帽子  -好可愛啊
-That bonnet. -Isn't it just too adorable?
誰不喜歡這樣的聚會
Don't you love showers?
你真是美極了
I've never seen you look more beautiful.
容光煥發
Isn't she radiant?
我昨天就是這樣告訴比爾的
That's what I told Bill yesterday.
我說  "比爾  認識達玲以來
"Darling looks positively radiant.
從來沒見過她這么容光煥發"
Why, in all my days," I said, "I've never seen anyone as radiant."
吉姆  你怎么這副德性
Jim, you look terrible.
太可怕
Absolutely horrible.
你糟透了
I never saw you look worse.
吉姆  打起精神  你撐得過去的
Cheer up, Jim. Old Doc Jones has never lost a father yet.
四月
對  莎拉姑媽  是男孩
Yes, Aunt Sarah, it's a boy.
是男孩  是  什么
Uh-huh. A boy. And... What's that?
眼睛  眼睛的顏色
Eyes? Oh, what colour are they?
哦  我的天
Well, oh, gosh.
我忘了看
I forgot to look.
醫生  是男孩  是
A boy. It's a boy, it's a... Doctor!
醫生  是男孩
Doctor, it's a boy!
對  我知道
Yes, yes, I know.
是男孩
Uh-huh! A boy.
哦  老天
Oh, boy, oh, boy!
是男孩  是男孩
It's a boy, it's a boy, it's a boy!
喂  吉姆
Hello? Hello, Jim?
吉姆  你在嗎
Are you there, Jim?
總機  我們的電話被切斷了
Central, we've been cut off.
喂  喂
Hello? Hello?
喂
Hello!
什么是寶寶
What is a baby?
我真搞不懂
I just can't understand
它一定很奇妙
It must be something wonderful
很不尋常
It must be something grand
不然大家為什么
'Cause everybody's smiling
都笑得那么開心
In a kind and wistful way
甚至都沒
And they haven't even noticed
注意到我
That I'm around today
到底嬰兒是什么
What is a baby, anyway?
What is a baby?
我今天一定要搞清楚
I must find out today
為什么他們
What makes Jim Dear and Darling
會這樣
Act this way?
啦啦嚕
La la loo
我的小星星
Oh, my little star sweeper
我要替你擦掉
I'll sweep the stardust
星星上的灰塵
For you
啦啦嚕  啦啦嚕
La la loo La la loo
柔軟的小睡蟲
Little soft fluffy sleeper
蓋上一片
Here comes a pink cloud
粉紅的云彩
For you
啦啦嚕  啦啦嚕
La la loo La la loo
奇妙的小天使
Little wandering angel
收起你的翅膀
Fold up your wings
閉上你的雙眼
Close your eyes
啦啦嚕  啦啦嚕
La la loo La la loo
愿愛當你的守護神
And may love be your keeper
啦啦嚕  啦啦嚕
La la loo La la loo
啦啦嚕
La la loo
好啦
There, now.
我的小星星
Little star sweeper.
入夢吧
Dream on.
這些應該夠了
Well, that should do it.
我們的行李  差不多夠玩到中國了
We've got enough here to take us halfway to China.
達玲  達玲
Darling. Darling!
我們時間不多了
We haven't much time.
吉姆  我真的舍不得
Jim, I just can't leave him.
他還這么小  需要人照顧
He's still so small and helpless.
他會沒事的
He'll be all right.
走吧  如果他醒過來  我們就走不了了
Now come on. If he wakes up, we'll never get away.
吉姆  丟下他我有罪惡感
Jim, I feel so guilty deserting him like this.
胡說
Nonsense.
嘿  麗滴怎么啦
Hey. What's the matter with Lady?
她以為我們要丟下寶寶
She thinks we're running out on him.
別擔心  大女孩
Aw. Don't worry, old girl.
我們過幾天就回來
We'll be back in a few days.
莎拉姑媽會在這里
And Aunt Sarah will be here.
有你在這里幫她
With you here to help her...
她來了
Oh. There's the old girl now.
莎拉姑媽  請進
Coming, Aunt Sarah. Coming!
親愛的  抱歉我來晚了  希望沒耽誤你們的時間
Sorry I'm late, dears. Hope I haven't kept you waiting.
-我幫你拿東西  -不用了
-Let me take your things. -No, no, no, no.
別客氣  這里我熟得很
No fussing. I know my way around.
走吧  不然就趕不上火車了
On your way. Mustn't miss your train.
好好玩  一點都不用擔心
Have a good time, and don't worry about a thing.
親愛的  再見  再見  再見
Goodbye, dears. Goodbye.
再見
Goodbye.
該去看我的小外甥了
Now to see that big nephew of mine.
你這個可愛的
Oh, you adorable little...
老天  你在這里干嘛
Good gracious! What are you doing here?
走開  噓  不要待在這里
Go on, now. Shoo, shoo. Scat. Get out of here.
別哭  別哭
Aw, there, there.
莎拉姑媽  再也不準那只狗嚇你
Aunt Sarah won't let that dog frighten you any more.
不哭  不哭  不哭
No, no, no.
嬰兒輕輕搖  好像風兒
Rock-a-bye baby on the treetop
吹樹梢
When the wind blows...
我們是暹羅貓
We are Siamese if you please
We are Siamese if you don't please
我們正在找新房子
Now we looking over our new domicile
如果喜歡  我們就多住一陣子
If we like we stay for maybe quite a while
你有沒有看到那東西  游來游去
Do you seeing that thing swimming round and round?
有啊
Yes.
我們去把它弄下來
Maybe we could reaching in and make it drown.
如果我們偷偷把它弄下來
If we sneaking up upon it carefully...
那就魚頭給你
There will be a head for you
魚尾歸我
A tail for me
什么聲音
Do you hear what I hear?
嬰兒的哭聲
A baby cry.
有嬰兒就有牛奶
Where we finding baby there are milk nearby
如果我們去找嬰兒車  一定找得到
If we look in baby buggy there could be
很多牛奶  夠我們喝個夠
Plenty milk for you and also some for me
下面發生了什么事
What's going on down there?
老天  我的心肝寶貝
Merciful heavens! My darlings.
我的愛貓
My precious pets.
你這個討厭鬼
Oh. Ooh, that wicked animal.
欺負我無辜  可憐的小貓咪
Attacking my poor, innocent little angels.
寵物店
女士  午安
Good afternoon, ma'am.
需要什么嗎
What can I do for you?
我要一個  堅固一點的狗口罩
I want a muzzle. A good, strong muzzle.
沒問題  這是最新款
Oh, yes, ma'am. Now here's our latest.
有皮帶跟口罩
Combination leash and muzzle.
只要像這樣套上去
Now, we'll just slip it on like this,
就  不  不  不  不
and... No! No, no, no.
好狗狗  不要亂動
Nice doggy. No, don't wiggle.
別亂動  來  來  來
Steady, now. Now... Now, now.
小心  你這個小
Careful, you little...
小心
Watch out.
-狗狗  小心  -回來
-Careful, doggy. -Come back!
我說回來  回來
Get over here, I say. Come back here.
嘿  你怎么跑到這邊來了
Hey, Pige, what are you doing on this side of the tracks?
我以為你
I thought you...
怎么會
Wh...?
小可憐
Aw, you poor kid.
這要拿掉才行
Oh, we've got to get this off. Hmm.
我知道一個地方
I think I know the very place.
來
Come on.
到了
Well, here we are.
-動物園  -對
-The zoo? -Sure.
不  這邊
No, no. This way.
跟我來
Follow me.
-哦  -怎么啦
-Oh. -What's the matter, Pige?
-我們不能進去  -為什么
-We can't go in. -Why not?
禁止小狗進入
-牌子說  -對  那是
-The sign says... -Yeah, that's...
-隨便說說  -隨便說說
-That's the angle. -Angle?
只要有適當
Look. We'll wait for the right...
來了
Uh-oh. Here we are now.
蹲低
Just lay low.
-嘿  你  -什么
-Hey, you! -I beg your pardon.
-你叫我  -怎樣  你不識字嗎
-Were you addressing...? -What's the matter? Can't you read?
我精通數國語言呢
Why, yes, in several languages.
哦  聰明人
Oh, a wise guy, eh?
好  這個家伙在這里干嘛
All right, now, what's this creature doing here?
-這不是我的狗  -不是
-He's not my dog. -Oh, he's not, eh?
走開  下去
Go away. Get down.
快啊  警察先生  當然不是
Go on. Why, certainly not, officer.
是哦  我想你接下來  要告訴我
Aye. I suppose you'll be telling me next
口哨是狗吹的吧
it was the dog that was whistling, eh?
我真的不知道
I'm certain I don't know.
哦  那是我亂說了
Oh! So I'm a liar now, am I?
你聽我說
Well, you listen to me.
違抗執勤人員
Ah-ha! Resisting an officer of the law.
可是要付出代價的
You're gonna pay. Ow!
拿刀殺我啊
Pull a knife on me, will you?
想行刺我
Trying to assassinate me, you are.
私藏武器
Carrying concealed weapons.
麗滴  走吧
Come on, Pige.
沒人會管我們了
The place is ours.
我們最好從頭找起
We'd better go through this place from A to Z.
猩猩
Apes.
不  問他們也沒用  他們不懂
No, no. No use even asking them. They wouldn't understand.
是嗎
They wouldn't?
跟人類太像了
Uh-uh. Too closely related to humans.
鱷魚
鱷魚  有了
Alligators. Now there's an idea.
你可以  幫我們把這個咬斷嗎
Say, Al, do you suppose you could nip this contraption off for us?
十分樂意
Glad to oblige.
喔  喔
Whoa. Whoa!
土狼
該戴口罩的應該是他
Ha! If anybody ever needed a muzzle, it's him.
-樹倒了  -小心
-Timber! -Pigeon, look out!
水獺之家
什么樣的白癡
Now what harebrained idiot would...
嘿  看  是水獺
Hey, look. A beaver.
我們找到救星了
There's the answer to our problem.
我看看
Let me see here.
六個六尺  七個十六寸
Six-foot-six and seven-sixteenth inches.
朋友  打攪一下
Pardon me, friend.
-不知道你能不能  -小子  我很忙
-I wonder if you'd do us a little... -Busy, sonny. Busy.
沒時間閑扯
Can't stop to gossip now.
要把這個大樹拖到
Got to slide this sycamore to the...
水里
...swamp.
只耽誤你一秒鐘
Well, this will only take a second.
一秒鐘  聽著  小子
Only a second? Listen, sonny.
你知道每一秒  就有七十公分的水
Do you realise every second, 70 centimetres of water
從那個缺口流走嗎
is wasted over that spillway?
-對  但是  -小子  我要把這根木頭拖走
-Yeah, but... -Gotta get this log moving, sonny.
要把這根木頭拖走
Gotta get it moving.
切斷很花時間
'Taint the cuttin' takes the time.
該死
It's the doggone hauling.
用拖的  對
The hauling. Exactly.
-你需要的是  -我最好把它切咸兩斷
-Now, what you need... -I'd better bisect this section here.
你需要的是拉木頭的工具
What you need is a log puller.
我說拉木頭的工具
I said a log puller!
小子  我不是聾子
I ain't deaf, sonny.
不用這樣
There's no need to...
你剛說拉木頭的工具
Did you say log puller?
真巧  你眼前
And by a lucky coincidence you see before you,
這位漂亮小姐身上展示的  就是全新改良
modeled by the lovely little lady, the new, improved,
獲得專利的  專用拉木頭工具
patented, handy dandy, never-fail little giant log puller.
忙碌水獺的好幫手
The busy beaver's friend.
真的嗎
You don't say?
品質保證  堅固耐用
Guaranteed not to wear, tear, rip or ravel.
轉個圈  讓客戶仔細看看商品
Show the customer the merchandise.
節省百分之六十六  拖木頭時間
And it cuts log-hauling time 66 percent.
百分之六十六
Sixty-six percent, eh?
太好了
Think of that.
-要怎么用  -簡單得不得了
-Well, how's it work? -Why, it's no work at all.
只要把這個環  像這樣套在木頭上
You merely slip this ring over the limb like this
然后拉
and haul it off.
那
Uh, say...
我試用一下如何
You mind if I slip it on for size?
請便
Help yourself, friend.
好  借我用用怎么樣
OK. Don't mind if I do.
小子  怎么拿下來
How do you get the consarned thing off, sonny?
你問對了  你問對了
Glad you brought that up. Glad you brought that up.
只要把帶子  放在牙齒中間
To remove it, simply place the strap between your teeth...
像這樣
Like this?
對  然后用力咬
Correct, friend. Now bite hard.
看到沒
You see?
掉了
It's off.
真簡單
Say, that is simple.
我們要走了  所以
Well, friend, we'll be on our way now, so...
小子  等等
Uh-uh-uh. Not so fast now, sonny...
我要試用滿意了
I'll have to make certain it's satisfactory
才付錢啊
before we settle on a price.
不用了  是你的了
Oh, no, it's all yours, friend.
送你
You can keep it.
真的
Eh... I can, eh?
I can?
這是免費樣品
Uh-huh. It's a free sample.
太感謝了
Well, thanks a lot.
Thanks ever so...
嘿
Say!
真好用
It works swell.
當她把那個可怕的口罩  戴在我嘴上
But when she put that horrible muzzle on me...
不用再說了  我都知道
Say no more. I get the whole picture.
姑媽  貓  口罩
Aunts. Cats. Muzzles.
誰叫你要寄人籬下
Well, that's what comes of tying yourself down to one family.
你沒有家嗎
Haven't you a family?
一天換一個
One for every day of the week.
重點是  我不屬于他們
The point is, none of them have me.
我不懂你的意思
I'm afraid I don't understand.
很簡單
It's simple.
你看
You see...
嘿
Hey.
該吃晚餐了
Something tells me it's suppertime.
來  跟我走  你就知道了
Come on. I'll show you what I mean.
這是蘇茲家
Take the Schultzes here.
小費茲  他們都這樣叫我
Little Fritzie, that's me, Pige,
這是星期一的家
makes this his Monday home.
-星期一的家  -對啊
-Monday home? -Ach, ja.
星期一蘇媽媽
Monday's is Mama Schultz
會煮維也納炸肉片
cooking der Wiener Schnitzel.
非常好吃的
Mmm. Delicious.
這里是歐伯恩家  我在這里
Now, O'Brien's here is where little Mike,
叫小麥克
that's me again, Pige,
-星期二的家  -每星期二
-comes of a Tuesday. -Of a Tuesday?
對啊
Begorra.
有好吃的玉米牛肉
That's when they're after having their darling corned beef.
你看  當一個人自在逍遙
You see, Pige, when you're footloose and collar-free,
就能享受最好的
well, you take nothing but the best.
嘿  湯尼之家
Hey! Tony's!
湯尼之家
當然  特別的日子  該到特別的地方
Of course. The very place for a very special occasion.
來  我有專用入口
No, this way, Pige. I have my own private entrance.
在這里等我
Wait here.
等等  我來了  我
Just one minute. I'm a-coming. I'm...
搞什么  今天又不是愚人節
What's a-matter? Somebody's a-makin' da April Fool...
哦  是你
Oh, hello, Butch.
你怎么這么久沒來
Where you been so long?
嘿  喬  看看誰來啦
Hey, Joe, look who's here.
真想不到  是長云
Well, what do you know? It's Butch.
嘿  嘿  嘿
Hey, hey, hey!
喬  快拿點上好的骨頭來  不然長云要把我吃了
Joe, bring some bones for Butchy before he eat me up.
好  湯尼
OK, Tony. OK.
上好的骨頭來了
Bones a-coming up.
她是誰
What's this?
嘿  喬  你看
Hey, Joe, look.
長云交了新的女朋友
Butchy, he's got a new girlfriend.
好小子
Well, a son of a gun!
他交了一個長發妹
He's a got a cockerel Spanish a-girl.
嘿  長云  她真漂亮
Hey, she's a pretty sweet kiddo, Butch.
聽湯尼的話  跟炸個定下來好嗎
You take-a Tony's advice and a-settle down with this-a one, eh?
"炸個"
"This a-one?"
是這個  這  哦
This one. This... Oh!
你知道湯尼
Tony, you know.
他發音不標準
He's a-not a-speaking English a-pretty good.
首先準備張桌子
Now, first we fix-a the table.
-湯尼  你要的骨頭  -好骨頭
-Here's your bones, Tony. -OK, bones. Bones?
喬  你怎么搞的  我打你啊
What's the matter for you, Joe? I break-a your face.
今晚要請長云吃大餐
Tonight, Butch, he gets the best in the house.
好  湯尼  你是老板
OK, Tony, you the boss.
告訴我  你想吃什么
Tell me, what's your pleasure?
單點還是套餐
À la carte? Dinner?
好
Ah-ha. OK.
嘿  喬
Hey, Joe.
長云說
Butch-a, he says
他要兩份特調意大利面
he wants-a two spaghetti speciale.
牛肉丸多一點
Heavy on the meats-a ball.
湯尼  狗不會說話
Tony, dogs don't talk.
-他跟我說的  -好  他跟你說
-He's a-talking to me! -OK, he's a-talking to you.
你是老板
You the boss.
來
Now here you are.
城里最好吃的意大利面
The best spaghetti in town.
今夜
For this is the night
真美妙
It's a beautiful night
我們叫它
And we call it
愛的夜晚
Bella notte
仰望天空
Look at the skies
布滿星辰
They have stars in their eyes
就在這醉人的愛的夜晚
On this lovely bella notte
與愛人
Side by side
依偎
With your loved one
令人更加振奮
You'll find enchantment here
今夜織出神奇魅力
The night will weave its magic spell
當愛人就在你身旁
When the one you love is near
今夜
For
如
This is the night
置身天堂
And the heavens are right
就在這醉人的
On this lovely
愛的夜晚
Bella notte
這夜晚
This is the night
這美麗的夜晚
It's a beautiful night
我們叫它
And we call it
水泥未干
愛的夜晚
Bella notte
仰望天空
Look at the skies
布滿星辰
They have stars in their eyes
就在這醉人的
On this lovely
愛的夜晚
Bella notte
與愛人依偎
Side by side with your loved one
令人更加振奮
You'll find enchantment here
今夜織出神奇魅力
The night will weave its magic spell
當愛人就在你身旁
When the one you love is near
今夜
For this is the night
如同置身天堂
And the heavens are right
就在這醉人的
On this lovely
愛的夜晚
Bella notte
哦  老天
Oh! Oh, dear.
怎么啦
Is something wrong, Pige?
-天亮了  -對
-It's morning. -Yeah.
天亮了
So it is.
我早該回家了
I should have been home hours ago.
為什么  你還相信那一套  那套"忠狗"歪理
Why? Because you still believe in that "ever faithful old dog Tray" routine?
拜托
Aw, come on, Pige.
-眼睛擦亮一點  -眼睛擦亮一點
-Open up your eyes. -Open my eyes?
看看狗的世界可以多精彩
To what a dog's life can really be.
跟我走你就知道
I'll show you what I mean.
看看下面  你看到什么
Look down there. Tell me what you see.
我看到房子
Well, I see nice homes
有院子和籬笆
with yards and fences.
對  受拘束的生活
Exactly. Life on a leash.
再看看
Look again, Pige.
后面有個更大的世界
Look, there's a great big hunk of world down there
沒有籬笆圍住
with no fence around it.
我們可以去冒險  追求刺激
Where two dogs can find adventure and excitement.
看看更遠的地方
And beyond those distant hills,
誰知道還有什么奇妙的事
who knows what wonderful experiences?
都等著我們去追尋
And it's all ours for the taking, Pige.
都是我們的
It's all ours.
聽起來很棒
It sounds wonderful.
但是
But?
但是小寶寶怎么辦
But who'd watch over the baby?
你贏了
You win.
來吧
Come on.
我送你回家
I'll take you home.
捕狗隊
今夜真美妙
It's a beautiful night
我們叫它
And they call it...
不是要改變話題  但是
Not to change the subject, but, um...
你追過雞沒有
Ever chase chickens?
沒有
I should say not!
那你白活了
Oh, ho! Then you've never lived.
-這樣做不對  -我知道
-But we shouldn't. -I know.
所以才好玩啊
That's what makes it fun.
來吧
Aw, come on, kid.
留下些美好的回憶
Start building some memories.
但是  不會傷到雞吧
But we... We won't hurt the chickens?
傷到雞  不會
Hurt them? No!
只是攪和一下
We'll just stir them up a bit.
看他們一個個又肥又懶
Just look at those fat, lazy biddies.
他們早該起床了
Why, they should've been up hours ago.
好玩吧
Some fun, hey, kid?
嘿  怎么回事
Hey, what's going on in there?
怎么啦
What's that?
該開溜了  走吧
That's the signal to get going. Come on.
-人生就是要這樣  -是嗎
-This is living, hey, kid! -Is it?
來吧  跟我走
Come on, Pige. Follow me.
我們都有點打獵的本能
You know, there's a little bit of bird dog in all of us, eh, Pige?
麗滴  麗滴
Pige? Pige?
麗滴  你在哪
Pige? Where are you, Pige?
麗滴
Pige?
Pigeon?
哦  麗滴
Oh, Pige!
捕狗隊
嘿  大西  進行得怎么樣
Hey. Hey, Dachsie, how we coming?
再唱一段就好了
Just one more chorus and we're out.
好  第一拍開始
OK. On a downbeat.
一  二
One, two...
比爾  把她關到四號籠子
Put her in number four, Bill,
-我來檢查她的身份  -好
-while I check her licence number. -OK.
好  寶貝  進去
All right, baby, in here.
各位  來了個大小姐
Well, look yous guys, Miss Park Avenue herself.
老天
Blimey.
真是如花似玉
A regular bloomin' debutante.
還穿金戴銀呢
Yeah. And pipe the crown jewel she's wearing.
嘿  里面放心上人照片
Hey, whatcha in for, sweetheart?
還是收集跳蚤
Putting fleas on the butler?
好  大伙兒  走開好嗎
All right, you guys. Lay off, will you?
佩姬  怎么啦
Aw, what's the matter, Peg?
我們只是開開玩笑
We was only having a bit of sport, we was.
你們看不出來  她嚇得半死嗎
Can't you see the poor kid's scared enough already?
小姑娘  別理他們
Pay no attention, my little ochichernye.
沒錯
That's right, dearie.
他們沒有惡意
They don't mean no real harm.
這就是所謂的
It's like Gorky says in Lower Depths, quote:
"幸災樂禍"
"Miserable being must find more miserable being.
這樣他們就開心了
Then he's happy."
-說完了  -包子真是有學問
-Unquote. -Boris is a philosopher.
但是話說回來  小姐
Besides, little bublichki,
在這種地方戴項圈
wearing licence here,
原諒我這么說  就是
that is like waving, you should excuse the expression,
自討苦吃
red flag in front of bull.
我的項圈怎么啦
My licence? But what's wrong with it?
親愛的  沒什么
There ain't nothin' wrong with it.
偷偷告訴你  這里每一只狗
Confidential, there's not one dog here
會不惜犧牲一切  弄一個那樣的項圈
who would not give left hind leg for such a knick-knack.
親愛的  那是自由通行證  少了它
That's your passport to freedom, honey. Without it...
嘿  你們看
Hey. Hey, yous guys, look.
可憐的諾西被帶走了
Poor Nutsy is takin' the long walk.
他們要帶他去哪里
Where is he taking him?
好妹妹  有去無回的路
Through the one-way door, sister.
不準進入
你是說  他
You... You mean he's...
唉
Oh, well.
人生苦短  好好享受
A short life and a merry one.
對  長云的名言
Yeah, that's what the Tramp always says.
-長云  -那個家伙
-The Tramp? -Now there's a bloke
從來沒被抓過
what never gets caught.
城里每個捕狗隊員  都拿他沒輒
He's given the slip to every dogcatcher in this burg.
親愛的  你不會相信  不管被困在哪里
You won't believe this, dearie, but no matter how tight a jam he's in,
他總是有辦法逃出去
that Tramp always finds some way out.
我相信
I can quite easily believe that.
但記住  我的朋友
Ah, but remember, my friends,
長云也有他的弱點
even Tramp has his Achilles' heel.
對不起  什么是"肉點"
Pardon me, amigo. What is this "chilli heel"?
是弱點
Achilles' heel, Pedro.
就是致命傷
This is meaning his, uh... weaknesses.
對  女人
Oh. Oh, the dames. Yeah.
他喜歡漂亮的小妞
He has an eye for a well-turned paw, he has.
我看看  有露露
Let's see. There's been Lulu.
對  還有崔西
Yeah, and Trixie.
菲菲
Und Fifi.
還有我姐姐
And my sister,
露西塔
Rosita Chiquita Juanita Chihuahua.
應該沒錯
I think.
他真有一套
What a dog.
對  佩姬  唱來聽吧
Yeah. Tell us about it, Peg.
他真有一套
What a dog!
佩姬以前在歌舞劇團表演
Peg used to be in the Dog and Pony Follies.
他就是長云
He's a tramp
大家都愛他
But they love him
每天都有新花招
Breaks a new heart every day
他就是長云
He's a tramp
大家都崇拜他
They adore him
希望他永保風格
And I only hope he'll stay that way
他就是長云
He's a tramp
是惡棍
He's a scoundrel
浪子
He's a rounder
壞胚子
He's a cad
他就是長云
He's a tramp
可是我還是愛他
But I love him
即使他很壞
Yes, even I have got it pretty bad
你永遠不知道
You can never tell
他何時會出現
When he'll show up
他總帶來一堆麻煩
He gives you plenty of trouble
我想他是自命瀟灑
I guess he's just a no 'count pup
但我希望他永保風格
But I wish that he were double
-他是長云  -嘭  嘭
-He's a tramp -Bum-bum-bum-ruff
-四處流浪  -嘭  嘭
-He's a rover -Bum-bum-bum-ruff
無以形容
And there's nothin' more to say
長云
If he's a tramp
他是條好漢
He's a good one
希望我能像他一樣
And I wish that I could travel his way
Wish that I could travel his way
希望我能像他一樣
對
Yeah.
但他總是吊兒郎當
But he never takes them serious.
總有一天他會遇見心上人
Ah, but someday he is meeting someone different.
一個楚楚動人的美女
Some delicate, fragile creature
他愿意照顧  呵護她
who's giving him a wish to shelter and protect.
就像這位千金小姐對吧
Like Miss Park Avenue here, eh, matey?
可能
Hm-hm. Could be.
-但是當他  -對  我看得比你遠
-But when he does... -Yeah. I'm way ahead of ya.
在愛情的魔咒下
Under the spell of true love...
那個家伙一不小心
The poor chump grows careless...
就被捕狗隊抓走
The Cossacks are picking him up...
長云就完了
And it's curtains for the Tramp.
比爾  有點嬌那只
It's the little cocker, Bill.
-在四號籠子里  -好
-In number four. -OK.
好  來吧
All right, baby.
他們來帶你回家了
They've come to take you home.
這里不屬于你
You're too nice a girl to be in this place.
勇氣
Courage, man.
Courage!
但是
But, uh...
我沒想過要結婚
I've never even considered matrimony.
我也沒有
Nor I.
不管她選誰
But no matter which of us she accepts,
永遠不會破壞我們的友誼
we'll always be the best of friends.
記住
Now remember,
別提那件不幸的事
not a word about her unfortunate experience.
-我們不是來傷她的心  -對  對
-We don't want to hurt her feelings. -Uh, yeah. Yeah.
小美女
Lassie.
麗滴小姐
Miss Lady, ma'am.
拜托  我誰都不想見
Please, I don't want to see anybody.
小美女
Now, now, lassie.
不要這樣
Don't feel that way about it.
小美女  不要這樣
Of course not, Miss Lady.
我所見過最棒的那些人
Why, some of the finest people I ever tracked down
-通常都是常進出監獄的  -閉嘴
-were jailbirds. -Quiet!
你個白癡
You great loony!
拜托  小美女
Uh, please, lassie.
我們有個提議可以幫你
We've come with a proposition for helping ya.
幫我  什么意思
Help me? What do you mean?
嗯
Well, now...
小美女  你知道
You see, lassie...
我們兩個都不是年輕人了
Neither of us is as young as we used to be.
但還是處于巔峰狀態
But we're still in the prime of life.
對
Aye.
我們兩個人的家  都很舒服
And we've both got very comfortable homes.
對  我們都知道
That's right. Where we know
麗滴小姐  你會備受疼愛
you'll be welcome and appreciated, Miss Lady.
所以  講白一點就是
So... So, to come directly to the point...
如果你愿意
If you could, uh...
如果你不嫌棄
...find it possible to, uh...
可以
To, uh...
你們兩個都是好人  我很感謝你們
You're both very kind, and I do appreciate it.
-但是  -哦  麗滴
-But... -Oh, Pigeon.
哦  麗
Oh, Pi...
哦  嗨  大家好
Oh! Oh, hi, boys.
有什么新鮮事嗎
Anything new in the kennel club set?
麗滴  這個給你
A little something I picked up for you, Pige.
看來我不受歡迎
Looks like I'm the one that's in the doghouse.
麗滴小姐  如果你討厭這個家伙
If this person is annoying you, Miss Lady...
我們很樂意趕他出去
We'll gladly throw the rascal out.
那倒不必  謝謝你們
That won't be necessary. Thank you.
不客氣
Very well, ma'am.
你  你
You... You...
這個混混
...mongrel!
拜托  麗滴
Aw, come on, Pige.
-不是我的錯  -唔
-It wasn't my fault. -Hmph.
我以為你就跟在后面  真的
I thought you were right behind me. Honest.
當我聽說你被抓到
When I heard they'd taken you to the pound...
別再提那個恐怖的地方
Oh! Don't even mention that horrible place.
我覺得好丟臉而且
I was so embarrassed and...
-好害怕  -哦
-... and frightened. -Oh, now, now.
像你這么可愛的小妞  誰會欺負你
Who could ever harm a cute little trick like you?
小妞  小妞
Trick? Trick!
-這倒提醒我  崔西是誰  -崔西
-That reminds me, who is Trixie? -Trixie?
還有露露  菲菲  露西
And Lulu and Fifi and Rosita Chiquita wh...
-露西什么的  -露西
-Whatever her name is. -Chiquita...
哦  對  我
Oh! Yes! Well, I... I...
你用不著擔心你的臭弱點
As far as I'm concerned, you needn't worry about your old heel.
臭弱點
My heel?
我不用你照顧呵護
I don't need you to shelter and protect me.
-對  但是  -如果你不小心被抓  別怪我
-But... -If you grow careless, don't blame me.
就算你被抓走  我也不在乎  再見
I don't care if the Cossacks do pick you up! Goodbye.
把這個拿走
And take this with you.
不要叫了
Stop that.
噓  噓
Hush, now, hush.
不要再叫了
Stop that racket!
麗滴  怎么啦
What's wrong, Pige?
-老鼠  -在哪里
-A rat! -Where?
樓上的嬰兒房
Upstairs, in the baby's room!
-從哪里進去  -小門
-How do I get in? -The little door.
在走廊那邊
On the porch.
老天
Merciful heavens!
哦  可憐的小寶貝
Oh! Oh, you poor little darling.
謝天謝地你沒事
No, no, no. Thank goodness you're not hurt.
你們  你們兩個畜牲  退后
You... You vicious brutes. Back!
退后
Get back!
去啊  進去
Go on! Get back!
捕狗隊  對  我找捕狗隊來
The pound. The pound, that's it. I'll call the pound.
過來  你過來
Come here, you. Come here!
下來  下來
Come on, come on. Come along.
來啊  我現在就打電話找他們
I'll call them this minute.
那個畜牲在家里  我一刻都睡不好
I won't sleep a wink with that brute in the house.
喂  喂
Hello? Hello!
年輕人  我不管你是不是一個人在那
I don't care if you are alone there, young man.
我要你立刻來把他帶走
I insist you pick him up immediately.
達玲  看
Darling, look.
我的建議是  立刻把這個畜牲宰了
If you want my advice you'll destroy that animal at once.
別擔心
Don't worry, ma'am.
我們早就想抓他了
We've been after this one for months.
交給我們處理
We'll take care of him.
-這是  -怎么回事
-What do you suppose...? -Say, what's going on here?
先生  剛抓到一只流浪狗
Just picking up a stray, mister.
小子  快
Come on, giddap.
他當時正攻擊一個小寶寶
Caught him attacking a baby.
-老天  -我的寶寶
-Good heavens. -My baby.
莎拉姑媽
Aunt Sarah!
我第一眼看到他  就知道他不是好東西
I was certain he was no good the moment I first laid eyes on him.
對  但是
Yeah, but, uh...
我沒料到他會做出這種事
I never thought he'd do a thing like that.
我及時趕到  他們正在
Thank goodness I got there in time. There they were...
一定有誤會
No, I'm sure there must be some mistake.
麗滴不會
Lady wouldn't...
小心  那只狗沒綁起來  別讓她靠近寶寶
Watch out! That dog's loose. Keep her away.
胡說  她有事想告訴我們
Nonsense. She's trying to tell us something.
大女孩  怎么啦
What is it, old girl?
你想說
What are you try...
達玲  莎拉姑媽  過來
Darling, Aunt Sarah, come here.
-這是什么  -老鼠
-What is it, Jim? -Aah! A rat!
老鼠
A rat?
我們怎么沒想到
We should've known.
我誤會他了
I misjudged him.
真糟糕
Badly.
快  我們要去阻止那輛馬車
Come on. We got to stop that wagon.
我們不知道  他們往哪個方向走
But, man, we don't know which way they've gone.
我們聞得出來
We'll track them down.
然后呢
And then?
我們把他們攔下來
We'll hold them.
讓他們動彈不得
Hold them at bay.
現在呢
Now what?
味道  跟著這個味道
The scent. Follow the scent.
面對現實吧
Ach... Let's face it, man.
我們都知道你失去嗅覺
We both know you've lost your sense of smell.
捕狗隊
走開
Go on, get out of here.
Go on, get away.
走開
Easy. Go on, get away.
小心  小心
Watch it now. Watch it!
捕狗隊
嗨  麗滴
Hi, Pige.
好  通通看這里
All right, everybody, watch the birdy.
站好
Steady, now.
別動
Hold it.
煙太多了
I guess I used a little too much.
達玲  有客人來了
Darling, visitors.
客人
Visitors?
是加克
Why, it's Jock.
還有老查弟
And good old Trusty.
小心
Careful now, man.
小心  有點滑
Careful. It's a wee bit slippery.
對
Yes, yes.
好  會讓他們進來
All right, boy. We'll let them in.
不是你
No, no, not you, young man.
你要去睡覺了
You're going to take a nap.
圣誕快樂
Well, Merry Christmas.
請進  進來
Come in. If you'll just step into the parlour,
我去準備點心
I'll see about refreshments.
達玲  你把狗餅干放在哪兒
Darling, where did you put the dog biscuits?
莎拉姑媽寄來那盒
The box Aunt Sarah sent for Christmas.
吉姆迪爾  在廚房
In the kitchen, Jim, dear.
如假包換
Oh, no doubt about it.
眼睛像媽媽
They've got their mother's eyes.
對
Aye.
但也有點像爸爸
But there's a bit of their father in them too.
你終于有了項圈
Well, and I see you finally acquired a collar.
哦  對
Oh. Yes.
還有身份證
Complete with licence.
哦  對  新項圈
Oh, yeah, a new collar.
我一進門就聞到了
Caught the scent the moment I came in the house.
查弟
Trusty, I says,
查弟  有人戴了新項圈
Trusty, somebody's wearing a new collar.
當然  我的嗅覺
'Course, my sense of smell
可是很靈敏的
is very highly developed.
這是遺傳
Runs in the family, you know.
這下沒完沒了了
There'll be no living with him from now on.
就像我爺爺以前常說
As my grandpappy, Old Reliable, used to say...
我有沒有提過我爺爺
I don't recollect if I've ever mentioned Old Reliable before.
查弟叔叔  你從來沒提過
No, you haven't, Uncle Trusty.
沒有
Huh? I haven't?
那
Well, um...
就像我爺爺以前常說
As Old Reliable used to say...
他說
He'd say, uh...
Uh...
糟糕
Doggone.
你們知道
You know,
我完全忘了他說過什么
I clean forgot what it was he used to say.
保佑我
Peace, my children
善良的孩子
Of good will
保佑我善良的孩子
Peace, my children
平安
Peace
永
Be
跟隨
Still